Hello Namaskar Jai Hind Vande Mataram.  You are watching
Jio News and we have brought for you
quick big news of selected importance from the country, world and your state and city.  But
before that, if you have not subscribed to our channel, then
subscribe to the channel and turn on the bell notification
and like and
share this video as much as possible.  Today's question for you before looking at the big news.
How many times does a human heart beat in 1 minute on an average?  Option A 52
times, Option B 62 times, Option C 72 times and
Option D 82 times.  Answer this question by
commenting and tell us which state and city's
news do you want to see more?
Tell us by commenting so that we
can show more news of your state or city.  Let us now see
today's quick big news.
Petrol and diesel prices increased for the fourth time this month.
In Delhi, petrol became costlier by ₹2.61 and diesel by
₹2.71 per litre.  Oil companies have increased the price of
petrol by ₹2.61 per litre and
diesel by ₹2.71 per litre on May 25.
After this increase, the price of 1 liter petrol in Delhi has now become
₹12.12 and the price of diesel has become
₹95.20.  Let us tell you that the
fare of trucks and tempos will increase due to which
vegetables, fruits and ration coming from other states will become
expensive.
Farmers will have to spend more to run tractors and pumping sets,
which will increase the cost of grains.  There may
also be an increase in fares in public transport and school buses.   The
Supreme Court asked the NTA
what it had learnt from its past mistakes.  It is
sad that no lessons were learnt.  Also sought answers from the Centre and CBI on NEET paper leak.  The
Supreme Court has
reprimanded the National Testing Agency (NTA) in the NEET paper leak case.   The
court has said that it is sad that NTA did
not learn any lesson from the earlier paper leak case.  A bench of Justices P S Narasimha and
Alok Arakhe was hearing the petitions filed by Federation of
All India Medical Association (FIMA) and
United Doctors Front (UDF) and others.
During this,
he said that this matter had also
reached the Supreme Court in 2024.  Then a committee
was formed which gave many recommendations which were
also accepted.  The court directed the
NTA to file an affidavit by Thursday
stating the steps taken under Section 204
and the recommendations of the monitoring committee.  Along with this,
answers have also been sought from the Central Government and CBI.
Uniform Civil Code Bill introduced in Assam Assembly.
There is a provision for registration of live-in relationships.
Uttarakhand is the
third state after Gujarat.  The
Uniform Civil Code (UGC) Bill was
introduced in the Assam Assembly and was tabled by the
state's
Parliamentary Affairs Minister Atul Bora on behalf of Chief Minister Himanta Biswa Sarma.  This
bill was approved by the Cabinet two weeks ago.
This bill will be discussed on May 27
and if this bill is passed then Assam will
become the third such state in the country,
before this Uttarakhand and Gujarat have done so.
According to CM Sharma, Scheduled
Tribes in the hills and Scheduled Tribes in the
plains will come out of the purview of UCC.   Along with this,
traditional religious
customs, practices and rituals have
also been exempted.
Holding centres will be built in every district of Bengal to keep the infiltrators.  Suspected
foreigners will be kept for 30 days.  After investigation, it will be
handed over to BSF.  The
BJP government of West Bengal has increased its strictness against illegal infiltration.  The
government has directed
all districts to set up hoarding centres for suspected foreign
nationals and infiltrators awaiting deportation, in line with the implementation of the Dejected, Delete and Deport policy
[Music].
In the order issued on May 23, the district administration has been asked to
create such centres where the
arrested suspected foreigners can be kept and the
suspected foreigners can be kept in such centres for a
maximum of 30 days.  During this period,
their documents, identity and citizenship will be checked.
Government incurs loss of ₹1 lakh crore due to reduction in petrol and diesel duty.
Finance Minister Nirmala
Sitharaman said that it is wrong to create a negative environment on the country's growth.
Sitharaman said that by reducing the excise duty on petrol and diesel, the
government will suffer a revenue loss of ₹1 lakh crore.  Along with this,
he rejected the pessimistic atmosphere being
created regarding India's economic growth
and
defended the economic condition of the country.  The Finance Minister
said this at the 37th Foundation Day celebrations of Small Industries Development Bank of India (ASIDBI) in Mumbai.
Trump called Modi great.  Said PM is
my friend.  I am a big fan of his.
India can trust me 100%.
US President Donald Trump
called PM Modi his great friend and said that
he is a big fan of PM Modi.  Trump
said that India can trust America 100%.
Trump
addressed the gathering by calling US Ambassador Sergio Gad at the India Pavilion in Delhi to mark America's 250th Independence Day.
He said that I love India.
Ambassador Gaur, as the representative of our country, will have to
give a good speech and
I would like to say good evening to everyone.  I
love the Prime Minister.  PM Modi
is great.  He is my friend.  Say hello to Modi.
I am a big fan of him.
Manisha Havaldar leaked the NEET paper for money.  After
asking the question, he deleted the chat with Mandhare.
Burn the notes.  CBI got six days
remand.  Let us tell you that the
Physics teacher arrested from Pune in the NEET UG paper leak case
is accused of sharing
exam-related
questions and content with some students in exchange for money.  The CBI had
given this information in the Pune court and later
Manisha was brought to the Rauch Revenue Court in Delhi.
Special Judge Ajay Gupta has
sent him to CBI custody for 6 days.
CBI had sought Manisha's custody for questioning and
confronting her with the remaining accused.  The
CBI had
arrested the constable on May 22.   In
fact,
Havaldar, Principal of Seth Hiralal Saraf School, was working
as a translator for the empanelled Physics paper of NEET UG 2026
and Manisha,
along with the other accused, had
circulated the Physics questions that were meant for
translation.
Trump said he will not make a deal with Iran like Obama.  There will be a
good deal or nothing will happen.
Expressed displeasure at opposition leaders.  US President Donald Trump
said that he will not make a deal like Obama with Iran.
He said that either there will be a good
agreement or nothing will happen.
Trump has
expressed displeasure at leaders who criticized the agreement with Iran.
He wrote on social media that
even those who do not know anything about the agreement with Iran are speaking
ill of it.  Trump said that
these people are weak and only divide the country.
Trump also said that his potential
agreement would not be like the 2015 nuclear deal.
Trump called Obama's deal a disaster
and claimed it
opened the way for Iran to acquire nuclear weapons.
Premanand ji's appeal, whether I am there or not, I will
always be with you. Forget my worries,
concentrate on Shri ji. The padayatra has been stopped for 9 days after my health deteriorated. Don't
worry at all, whether
we meet or not, whether we speak or not, we all
love you very much. The last thing is that you should
not worry, nor should you worry about
how we will rise,
we will be in your mind without saying anything. This Bhaavu Kapil has said this to
his disciples and devotees in Vrindavan by releasing a video.  The
1 minute 19 second video was
uploaded on the YouTube channel of Kekunj Ashram Trust.
Premananda Maharaj's night or padayatra
is closed from 17th May i.e. for 9 days.  The disciples had then told that
Premananda Maharaj was not well
and he was not even having private meetings with the devotees.
Both the kidneys of Premananda Maharaj
are damaged.  He undergoes dialysis two to three times a week.
Trump told Muslim countries to
recognize Israel.  Iran
will expand the Abraham Accords after the war ends.
Pakistan's problems will increase.  Trump has
called on Muslim countries to improve relations with Israel and has spoken to several leaders, including Mohammed
bin Salman, Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, Tamim
bin Hamad Al Thani, Asim Munir, Recep
Tayyeb Adgar and Abdel Fattah al-Sisi,
Abdullah II and Hamad bin Isa Al
Khalifa.
Trump wrote on social media that America has
worked very hard to resolve the Iran crisis.  Therefore, it is now necessary that all these
countries join the Abraham Accord.  That is,
improve relations with Israel and the
countries he named
included Saudi Arabia, Qatar, Pakistan, Turkey, Egypt and Jordan.
China said, India should stay away from the Dalai Lama successor
issue.  This is our internal matter.
External interference in the Tibet issue is not acceptable.
China has advised India to stay away from the issue of Dalai Lama's succession.
Beijing said the
process of determining the reincarnation and successor of the Dalai Lama
is entirely China's internal matter and no
external interference will be allowed.
Yujing, spokesperson of the Chinese Embassy in India, issued a statement saying
that the reincarnation of the Dalai Lama takes place as per centuries-old
religious customs and historical
traditions.  He said that
approval of the central government of China is necessary for this process and the 14th
Dalai Lama was also recognized under this process.  The
Chinese Embassy
also reminded India of its long-standing position on Tibet
and said in the statement that India should
not provide a platform for activities related to Tibetan independence
and this is important for regional stability and India-
China relations.
Nautapa starts, heat and warmth will increase.
Brahmapuri in Maharashtra is the
hottest in the country at 47.2°C.  After the
mercury reached 45 degrees Celsius in eight cities of MP and UP,
Nautapa has started in the country and
this means that there will be more heat in the next 9 days.
Heat waves and temperatures will also
increase.  The temperature may remain above 45 degrees Celsius.
Brahmapuri in Maharashtra's Vidarbha region
remained the hottest city in the country for the third consecutive day.  The
temperature here was 47.2° Celsius, which is
4.6° Celsius more than normal.
Banda was the hottest district in Uttar Pradesh with a temperature of 46.8° Celsius.
Apart from this,
45.6° Celsius in Prayagraj and Ui and 45.6° Celsius in Jhansi.
Whereas a temperature of 45.4° Celsius was recorded in Agra.
Whereas a
temperature of 45.2° Celsius was recorded in Hamirpur.
High Court notice to retired judge mother-in-law in actress Tisha case.  MP government said they are
not helping in the investigation.
CBI team leaves for Bhopal from Delhi.  In the actress Tisha
Sharma death case, the Madhya Pradesh High Court has
issued a notice to the accused mother-in-law and retired judge Giribala Singh on
a petition filed by the state government and Tisha's husband Navnidhi Sharma,
opposing Giribala's anticipatory bail granted by the trial court.  During the hearing,
Advocate General Prashant Singh, appearing for the government,
said that Giribala is not cooperating in the investigation.
Meanwhile, Giribala Singh's lawyer
Mrigendra Singh said that it is wrong to say
that we are not supporting the investigation.
We have not received the petition documents.
Therefore, time is required to file the reply.
Demand for early hearing of petition against Cockroach Janata Party.  The Supreme Court said, do
n't be so emotional.  The party has
22.9 million followers on Instagram.  The Supreme
Court refused to immediately hear the demand for a CBI investigation into the activities of persons associated with the Cockroach Janata Party.
Cockroach Janata Party is a
social media platform that emerged after the
recent cockroach comment by Chief Justice of India Surya Kant.
By 12:00 pm on Monday, CJP's Instagram
account had 22.9 million followers.
Petitioner's lawyer NK
Goswami said in the court that the CJP is
tarnishing the image of the judiciary.  After this, the bench of CJI and
Justice Joymalay Bagchi and Justice Vipul
Pancholi said that do
not take it so emotionally.
Three AIADMK MLAs
resigned from the Assembly.
Minister Adhav met Arjuna to join the TV.
Three AIADMK MLAs in Tamil Nadu
submitted their resignation to the Assembly Speaker.
Following the resignation, Madhuranthakam MLA
Maragatham Kumar Vel, Dharapuram MLA Satya
Bhama and Parai MLA Jai Kumar
reached the TV channel to meet leader Aadhav Arjuna.
Gulmarg ropeway in Kashmir suddenly stopped.
About 300 tourists were left hanging in the air.  The army has
evacuated 80 so far.  Rescue is being done with ropes and ladders.  It is the
third
highest ropeway in the world.
Gulmarg Gondola Jump, the world's third highest ropeway in Jammu and Kashmir, developed a
technical snag.  At
around 2:30 pm, all the cabins of the ropeway suddenly
stopped and more than 300 tourists
sitting on them got stuck mid-air.  These
included women, children and the elderly, and
many tourists panicked and started crying and screaming.
According to the Army, 65 cabins were stuck in the air
and each cabin can accommodate six people and till now
80 people have been safely evacuated from 16 cabins.
Many videos of the incident have
also surfaced.  In which rescue
teams are seen bringing people down with the help of ropes and stairs.
SDRF, NDRF teams
are also present at the spot.  The rescue operation is likely to continue till late night
and no one has been reported injured so far.
Hearing in Rahul Gandhi case postponed.  The
next debate will be held on June 1.  It was said in America that Lord
Ram is imaginary.  He did
not appear even at the last hearing.  The hearing against Congress MP Rahul Gandhi took place
in the MP MLA Court of Varanasi
and the case was heard before Additional District
Judge Yadavendra Vikram Singh.
In the case of plaintiff Harishankar Pandey vs Rahul Gandhi, no appearance was recorded on behalf of Rahul Gandhi when called.   On
the other hand, advocates Harishankar
Pandey and Alakh Narayan Singh have continued the debate on behalf of the plaintiff side.  The
Additional District Government
Advocate was also present in the court during the hearing and the
court has fixed June 1, 2026 for the next hearing and debate in the case.
Today
's thought: Be careful with small expenses
because a small hole can
sink even the biggest ship.  Do let us know how you liked this
video in the comment section.   If you
like the video then please like and
share the video and [Music] To watch such interesting
videos subscribe to our channel Jio
News and press the bell icon
and do check
our [Music]
playlist and community tab to watch our old and latest videos.
So see you in the next video.
Thank you for now.  [music]